# PITHAYUTH (WILL) CHARNSETHIKUL

pithayuth.me | linkedin.com/pithayuth | charnset@usc.edu

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research focuses on understanding human behaviors around cybersecurity through variety of data such as networks, system, and social media. The goal is to apply my specializations in machine learning and NLP with my security expertise to enhance user's security experiences as well as privacy.

### EDUCATION

University of Southern California, Ph.D., Computer Science

Los Angeles, California 2021-present

Advisors: Dr. Jelena Mirkovic

University of Southern California, M.S., Computer Science

Kasetsart University, B.Eng., Computer Engineering

Los Angeles, California

Specialization: Computer Networks

Bangkok, Thailand

2014-2018

2019-2021

# **ACADEMIC EXPERIENCES**

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

August 2021-Present

USC Information Sciences Institute (ISI), STEEL: Security Research Lab

Marina Del Rey, California

• Phishing: build a dialogue system that not only responses to the phishers but also elicits their information.

### **Student Worker, Research**

August 2019-May 2021

USC Information Sciences Institute (ISI), STEEL: Security Research Lab

Marina Del Rey, California

- Venmo: build a neural classifier that categorizes Venmo public transactions into multiple sensitive classes.
- Cloud Misbehavior: identify which /24 network prefixes are "cloud", then quantify the amount of bad traffic originated from these networks.
- DDoS Detection: implement various anomaly detection approaches and evaluate them with the captured traffic.

**Directed Research** August 2020-May 2021

Mentor: Dr. John Heidemann

Remote

• DNS latency: modify DNS servers to solicit TCP from selected clients, allowing us to determine RTTs.

**Teaching Assistant** 

January 2023-Present

USC Viterbi Department of Computer Science

Los Angeles, California

• CSCI 567: Machine learning, Spring 2023, Instructor: Dr. Yan Liu

### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCES**

# **Technical Intern**

June 2022-August 2022

AT&T Labs Research, Mentor: Dr. Anestis Karasaridis

Remote

- DNS data collection and analysis, specifically for DNS-over-TLS (DoT) and DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH).
- Add DNS source code (PowerDNS dnsdist) to extract session ID and user-agent from DoT/DoH queries and create a data pipeline to transfer and enrich data between Azure environment and Snowflake.
- Analyze collected data on Azure Databricks.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- GLOBECOMM 2022: AMON-SENSS: Scalable and Accurate Detection of Volumetric DDoS Attacks at ISPs; Rajat Tandon, Pithayuth Charnsethikul, Michalis Kallitsis, Jelena Mirkovic
- PETS2022: I know what you did on Venmo: Discovering privacy leaks in mobile social payments; Rajat Tandon, Pithayuth Charnsethikul, Ishank Arora, Dhiraj Murthy, Jelena Mirkovic Acceptance Rate: 21.02% (33/157)
- PAM2022: Old but Gold: Prospecting TCP to Engineer and Live Monitor DNS Anycast; Giovane C. M. Moura, John Heidemann, Wes Hardaker, Pithayuth Charnsethikul, Jeroen Bulten, João M. Ceron and Cristian Hesselman **Best Paper Award**
- · CloudNet2020: Quantifying Cloud Misbehavior; Rajat Tandon, Jelena Mirkovic, Pithayuth Charnsethikul

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, C, C++, Bash, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Typescript, SQL, JAVA, Perl, LTEX Frameworks: scikit-learn, PyTorch, Torch, TensorFlow, Keras, Huggingface, Angular, Node.js, Spark

**Packages and Tools**: NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, Git, Docker, MySQL **Platforms**: Linux, macOS, Windows, Arduino, Raspberry, GCP, Azure **Networking**: tcpdump, Wireshark, Nmap, Knot DNS, dnsdist

## **GRADUATE COURSEWORK**

Analysis of Algorithms, Applied Cryptography, Foundations of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Advanced Natural Language Processing, Robustness and Generalization in Natural Language Processing, Advanced Operating Systems, Computer Networking, Security Systems

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Deep Learning Specialization by DeepLearning.Al, Coursera

### **REFERENCES**

- Dr. Jelena Mirkovic, Research Associate Professor, USC ISI, mirkovic@isi.edu
- Dr. Genevieve Bartlett, Senior Computer Scientist, USC ISI, bartlett@isi.edu